jeunesseglobal.com 2019-08-22

# Privacy Policy | Jeunesse Global

_Last updated March 6, 2019_

Ensuring the security of the personal information you submit is a priority of Jeunesse Global. Our Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine quality products and services with integrity in dealing with our users and reflects our commitment to your privacy and security.

By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of information by Jeunesse as described in this Privacy Policy.

Jeunesse adheres to the privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

This privacy policy covers the collection and use of data through the web sites designed for our distributors, and includes the following domains: jeunesseglobal.com, jeunesseglobal2.com,jeunessemail.com, and through domains designed for retailing products directly to customers in the U.S. market: (shop.jeunesseglobal.com, betheenvy.com, monavie.com, buym1nd.jeunesseglobal.com, buyreserve.jeunesseglobal.com, zenproject8.com, yes2nv.com, yes2monavie.com, yes2luminesce.com, yes2reserve.com, yes2revitablu.com; yes2zen.com), all of which are collectively referred to as the “Websites”. This privacy policy also covers the collection and use of data through the, JMobile™, Shop Jeunesse, and Instantly Ageless™ smart phone applications, (collectively, the “Smart Phone Apps”). The Websites and Smart Phone Apps are collectively referred to as the “Jeunesse Site”.

We want your use of the Jeunesse Site and the services we offer to be productive and safe and we have taken great efforts to keep your information confidential and secure at all times within our system.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Doug Whitehead at [privacy@JeunesseHQ.com](mailto:privacy@jeunessehq.com)

Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services.

## EU-US Privacy Shield Policy 

If you access a Website from the European Union, please note that we are subject to the provisions of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the data protection regulations of your respective EU member state. In addition, Jeunesse complies with the Privacy Shield Framework agreement drawn up between the U.S. and the European Union and between the U.S. and Switzerland; Jeunesse has accordingly obtained certification. In doing so, Jeunesse undertakes to comply with the standards and requirements of European data protection law. Further information can be found on the web page linked below: [www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TRdWAAW&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TRdWAAW&status=Active/)

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Jeunesse commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with questions or concerns about the use of their Personal Data should contact us at: [privacy@JeunesseHQ.com.](mailto:privacy@JeunesseglobalHQ.com)

If your question or concern cannot be satisfied through this process Jeunesse has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield to an independent dispute resolution mechanism operated by JAMS, a global arbitration center for personal data and privacy matters. 

If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Jeunesse, EU and Swiss individuals may bring a complaint before the JAMS EU and Swiss Privacy Shield program that can be found at: <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. Finally, as a last resort and in limited situations, EU and Swiss individuals may seek redress from the Privacy Shield Panel, a binding arbitration mechanism. 

Jeunesse commits to cooperate with EU and Swiss data protection authorities (DPAs) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship. 

## Personal Information

The Jeunesse Site collects different types of personal identifiable information (PII) such as name, address, email address and phone number.

When you download and use the Smart Phone Apps, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier. We do not ask for, access or track any location based information from your _JMobile_ at any time while downloading or using JMobile. However, we do ask for, access and track location based information when using the [IA App].

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services, we may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products, and contact preferences.

Generally, you can visit the Jeunesse Site without entering any PII. However, if you choose to place an order on the Jeunesse Site, we require that you provide your name, mailing address, billing address, email address, phone number, credit card number and its expiration date.

All of this information is necessary for us to complete the transaction and notify you of your order status.

For distributors, the purpose of the Jeunesse Site is to manage your distributorship, preferred customers and network of distributors. If you are a distributor, the Jeunesse Site allows you to order products and manage your distributorship.

In order to use _JMobile_ or the backoffice of the Websites, you must have a Distributor Login provided by Jeunesse.

When enrolling to become a Jeunesse distributor through the Websites, we collect your PII, including your name, home or business address, telephone numbers, email address, IP address, credit card number and expiration date, bank account information (for direct deposit or direct debit), and various government-issued identifying data, including, but not limited to, your passport number, tax identification number, national ID card number, social insurance number, etc. We may also collect scanned copies of government-issued photo ID’s.

This data is necessary to manage your Jeunesse distributorship for purposes of identifying who you are, placement of your distributorship and of downline distributorships in the tree, compliance management, product ordering, recognition and rewards, and commissions calculations and payment.

We permit your upline to see only the following PII: your name, the country in which you are registered, your user name, and your sponsor’s name.

We permit your sponsor to see your name, email address and phone number.

If you choose to use a replicated website, we will display the PII that you expressly choose: name, Site URL, phone number.

We also collect third party personal information from customers, including their name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number and expiration date.

This PII is used to charge for product orders and ship product and for no other purposes.

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information Collected Automatically

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, domain type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Smart Phone Apps on your device. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the Smart Phone Apps.

## Supplementation of Information

In order to protect your account, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third party sources.

We use services from leaders in the industry to verify your identity, in order to prevent others from defrauding your account or the company.

## Testimonials/Product Reviews

If you provide a testimonial or product review on the Jeunesse Site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.

For testimonials, we do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting his or her name and video testimonial.

If you enter a comment in a public forum we are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these comments.

If you want to remove your personal information that is being displayed on the Jeunesse Site under public pages, please contact us at [privacy@Jeunessehq.com](mailto:privacy@jeunessehq.com)

## How We Use Your Information

We may use your email address, mailing address and/or phone number to provide quality customer support or to reach you regarding order status, product or fulfillment issues and other customer service related activities.

We may use your email address, mailing address and/or phone number to contact you regarding new product offerings, special sales, newsletters, market research, and enforcement of the distributor contract and other aspects of your use of the Jeunesse Sites.

If, however, you do not wish to receive such communications, you have the ability to "opt-out" at any time and you will not be contacted further, unless you place a product order. In that case, we will send you an order confirmation.

From time to time, we may ask you to answer surveys regarding current or future Jeunesse products, as well as to determine hours worked at each rank in the compensation plan. Participation in these surveys is always optional. Survey responses are only used in the aggregate, and are never linked to an individual.

We may occasionally share the aggregate survey data with our affiliates and development partners in order to facilitate new product development and improve customer service and overall customer satisfaction.

## Information Sharing and Choice

Jeunesse is not an "information broker”

We do not engage in the selling of the profile, contact, web usage habits, behavior, buying patterns, or demographic information of our customers, partners or users.

We use the information we collect about you to process orders, pay commissions and provide the best and most personalized service possible.

We will not use or share the PII provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first letting you know and offering you a choice. We will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited direct marketing materials from us and we will do everything we can to honor such requests.

## Agents/Service Providers

We use third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services.

We use Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order.

When you purchase a product and use our site, we will share your name, address, telephone number, and email address as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for promotional purposes or any other purpose aside from what is necessary to _provide_ services to us.

## Business Transition

In the event Jeunesse goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred.

You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

## Legal Disclaimer

In addition to the circumstances described above, Jeunesse may disclose or release information when we, in good faith, believe that doing so is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with the law, judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site; (ii) to enforce or apply the terms of User Agreement; or (iii) to protect the rights, property or safety of Jeunesse Sites, our users, or others.

## Links to Other Sites

This Jeunesse Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Jeunesse.

Please be aware that we, Jeunesse, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information.

**This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Jeunesse Site.**

## Social Media Widgets

Our Websites includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site.

These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a _cookie_ to enable the feature to function properly.

Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our web site.

Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Tracking Information

Jeunesse does not track users of Jeunesse Site online activity over time or allow other parties to do this on the Jeunesse Site.

## Log Files

Like most every web site, the Jeunesse Site records certain tracking information any time someone visits the site.

For every web page that is viewed, our web server records an IP address, the operating system, browser version and the name of the page that was viewed.

We use a third-party tracking service that uses tracking technologies to track non-personal information about visitors to our site.

This information is not linked to any specific user and is used in the aggregate to maintain, track performance and improve the Jeunesse Sites.

## Cookies

A _cookie_ is a small piece of information that is stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive.

The Jeunesse Site uses _cookies_ for the sole purpose of uniquely identifying our users and securing their personal information.

We also use _cookies_ to track your order process without requiring reentry or re-verification of password or personal information on each page of the site.

Rather than storing this information on Jeunessess server, the _cookie_ is stored in your computer and is activated only when you visit the Jeunesse Site.

Your privacy and security are not compromised when you accept a _cookie_ from the Jeunesse Site.

No one can access the information except Jeunesse.

## Third Party Tracking Technologies

Some of our business partners use cookies and web beacons on our site.

We do not have access or control over these third party trackers.

## Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We may employ a software technology called clear gifs (aka Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.

Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to _cookies_ , and are used to track the online movements of Web users.

In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information.

We may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients.

This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “How We Use Your Information”

## Flash _Cookies_

We do not use Flash _cookies_ to collect and store information.

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services and will use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Email & "Opt Out" Policy

We may use your email address provided to contact you regarding the following:

1 User Registration Status (including confirmation of account signup);

2 Order Status and Shipping Notification

3 Online Customer Satisfaction Survey

4 Major changes to the website, addition of new products or services;

5 Promotional and marketing materials that we think you may find useful

If you desire not to receive information about products or services we think may be of interest, you can change the notification options in your account settings.

If you wish to not receive any of these emails, you may _opt-out_ by clicking the Opt-Out link or submitting your email address to unsubscribe@Jeunesseglobal.com or by following the unsubscribe instructions within each email communication.

## Protecting Your Personal Information

Jeunesse is committed to ensuring the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We place a priority on protecting your Personally Identifiable Information and take commercially reasonable measures to secure and protect such information.

The Jeunesse Sites use secure sockets layer (SSL) to encrypt the transfer of sensitive information, such as your account password and billing information including credit card, from your web browser to our web server.

Only the last four (4) digits of your credit card number will be displayed in your account.

When you place an Order with us, you are given an opportunity to select if you wish to have your credit card numbers stored on our system.

Emails you send to us may not be secure unless otherwise told that security measures will be in place prior to your transmitting the information. For this reason, we ask that you do not send confidential information such as credit card numbers or account numbers to us through emails

The same SSL protocol also acts to authenticate the Jeunesse Sites and prevent unauthorized "hackers" from masquerading as any of our sites while you are logged in to your account. This is accomplished through a "digital certificate", which is an unforgettable electronic "identity card".

If another website attempts to falsely identify itself as a Jeunesse site, your web browser will display a warning indicating that there is a problem with the digital certificate for the Jeunesse Site. Do not log in to those sites if you see any such warning.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@jeunessehq.com](mailto:privacy@jeunessehq.com)

## Updating Your Personal Information

Preferred customers and distributors can update or correct their personal information at any time by visiting the "My Profile" section of the Jeunesse Site.

If you wish to access, delete or correct your information, please fill out a help desk ticket through your JOffice or contact us by telephone.

Requests for access will be responded to within 30 days of the request.

## Children’s Policy

The Website is not intended for use by children, and children under the age of 13 are not authorized to use the Website and should not submit any personal information to us. We do not knowingly market to or solicit information from children under the age of 13.

## Changes in this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.
